A War Never Ends
Da 5 Bloods is a war, drama film directed by Spike Lee.
Four African-American Vietnam veterans return to Vietnam.
They are in search of the remains of their fallen squad
leader and the promise of buried treasure.
These heroes battle forces of humanity and nature while confronted by
the lasting ravages of the immorality of the Vietnam War.
Paul, played by Delroy Lindo.
David, played by Jonathan Majors.
Otis, played by Clarke Peters.
Eddie, played by Norm Lewis.
Melvin, played by Isiah Whitlock Jr..
Hedy Bouvier, played by Mélanie Thierry.
Da 5 Bloods is a 2020 American war drama film directed,
produced, and co-written by Spike Lee.
It stars Delroy Lindo, Jonathan Majors, Clarke Peters, Johnny Trí Nguyễn, Norm Lewis, Isiah Whitlock Jr., Mélanie Thierry, Paul Walter
Hauser, Jasper Pääkkönen, Jean Reno, and Chadwick Boseman (in his final film role to be released during his lifetime).
The film's plot follows a group of four aging Vietnam War veterans who return to the country in search of the
remains of their fallen squad leader, as well as the treasure they buried while serving there.
Originally written by Danny Bilson and Paul De Meo in 2013, the script was re-worked by Lee and
Kevin Willmott following the pair's successful collaboration in BlacKkKlansman (2018).
The cast joined in February 2019 and filming began a month later,
lasting through June and taking place in Southeast Asia.
With a production budget of $35–45 million, it is
among Lee's most expensive films.
Da 5 Bloods was released by Netflix on June 12, 2020.
It received acclaim from critics, who praised the direction, themes, and the performances of
Lindo, Peters and Boseman, with many considering it among Lee's best works.
The film received numerous accolades, including nominations for the Academy Award for Best Original Score and Screen Actors Guild Award for
Outstanding Performance by a Cast in a Motion Picture, and was named by the National Board of Review as the Best Film of 2020.
The film explores themes of vietnam war, vietnam
veteran, gold, vietnam, war veteran.
The tone is emotional.